残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて到達
もっと走る熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
Shinji knows where they are. Katsuragi, the truth is with you. Don't hesitate. Move ahead. If I can see you again, I will say the words that I could not say eight years ago. Bye.
Another phone that will never ring.
Misato's shutting herself off again. As usual.
Is Asuka going to come back today?
She skips school. She won't go home. All she does is play those games.
Kari? Uh, yes? Can I sleep here?
Yeah.
I'm sorry I'm inconveniencing you.
You're not inconvenient.
Asuka.
When I didn't win with my Ava, I lost whatever value I might have had.
I hate.
I hate everything.
And I hate myself the most.
I don't care about anything anymore.
There's no point.
There's nothing to be ashamed of, Asuka. You did the best you could. You should be proud.
So, that child is gone.
Yes. Even cats die.
Don't cry, Grandma.
Yes, I'll come home as soon as I have time.
I haven't visited mother's grave in three years.
Yes, I'll call you next time.
Yeah, so even cats can die.
It is impossible to retrieve the land so long in us now.
Why did you use it?
And about the Ava series, we don't have them all scheduled yet.
Destroying the Angels is our top priority. There was no other way.
No other way? You'd better come up with a more believable excuse.
Your actions these days belie a lack of respect for this committee.
Vyutski, I'm in conference.
Understood.
Another Angel is approaching. We must finish this later.
You're assuming you'll still have a seat here.
Are you going to betray us, Sikari?
I'll be there in 15 minutes. Sort at Unit 0 through the 32nd gate. Use Unit 2 as the backup.
No, I'm sorry. I don't have the authority to cancel the commander's freeze on Unit 1.
That's right. Bye.
It's another Angel, all right. Damn.
Unit 0 has launched. Advancing to intercept.
Unit 2, remain in the launch bay.
No. Move it out.
What?
No arguments. It might be useful as a decoy at least.
Right.
Ava Unit 2, ready to launch.
Here I am in this seat again. Am I even linked to this thing anymore?
Unit 2, advance to the 8th gate. Stand ready to move out as soon as your launch position is determined.
Even if I go, I'll just be a burden on the others.
Target approaching. It's past the final intercept line at Gora.
I just don't care anymore.
The target is above the Milwaukee Donny Valley, rotating in a fixed position.
Target's AT field is still active.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry. No excuse. Status report.
It looks like we're in a stalemate, Major.
He's right. The target's field pattern keeps cycling from blue to orange.
What does that mean?
The Magi aren't able to answer that question yet.
We just don't have enough solid data right now.
However, I'm certain that it's capable of assuming forms besides the one we see now.
So we can't attack first.
Rey, let's hold back and study it for a bit.
Oh, it's coming.
Rey, efface of action!
She can't! There's not enough time!
Contamination! The target's affecting Unit Zero!
Watch the status on Unit Zero's AT field!
Her AT field's up, but it's not stopping the Angel's energy probe!
Is the Angel trying to establish first-level contact with Unit Zero?
It must be!
We've got biocontamination invading Unit Zero!
Ava Unit Two, roll out!
Take some of that heat off of Rey!
Target's invasion of Unit Zero continuing!
This isn't good. More than 5% has already undergone biofusion.
Asuka, advance 300 meters and spread your AT field to maximum!
Then fire your pallet gun into the target's vex section!
Ava Unit Two, lift off!
What are you doing?
Asuka, move out now!
What's wrong with her?
She can't sink!
Her sink ratio is under 10%!
Asuka!
It... it just won't move.
It won't move!
She's just the target sitting out there!
Get her back!
Do it now!
Who is this?
You?
Myself?
And an Ava?
I sense somebody other than myself.
Who are you?
An Angel.
Are you one of the beings we call the angels?
Don't you want to become one with me?
No.
I am me, not you.
But you shall.
It's too late.
I will share part of my mind with you.
Let me share with you these emotions.
This is pain.
Do you feel this pain?
This pain?
No.
It's different.
Loneliness.
Yes.
Loneliness?
I don't understand.
You don't want to be by yourself, correct?
We are many, but you are alone.
You hate it, don't you?
That is what it is to be lonely.
That is what your mind is.
It is what fills your soul.
You are that sorrow.
Is this a tear?
Am I the one crying?
Ray!
I want Evangelion Unit 1 taken out of cryostasis.
Launch it immediately.
What?
I said launch it!
Yes, sir.
Why for her?
Am I so worthless you couldn't do this for me?
Spread your AT field to full!
Get way out of there now!
Right!
Ikari!
Ah!
Take my mind and soul to become one with Ikari.
You will not!
Her AT field's been reversed!
She's got viral contamination everywhere!
She's trying to contain the angel!
Ray, abandon Unit 0!
Get out of there!
I cannot.
If I leave Unit 0, the AT field will cease to be.
I will not let it be.
Ray, don't do it!
Her core is collapsing.
It's past critical.
Ah!
The targets disappear.
This operation is over.
Downgrade.
Alert status to condition Yellow!
Roger.
Shifting Alert status to condition Yellow.
What's the status of Unit 0?
I don't think the entry plug ejected.
Send out a rescue team, if there's anything left to rescue.
Dr. Akagi, we've located the plug!
Dr. Akagi.
Classify everything here as top secret.
Clean out the plug and destroy everything.
Understood. Do it now!
At last, we have defeated all of the angels up to the 16th.
Now there's only one left.
As it is written in Zele's Dead Sea Scrolls.
The promised time is at hand.
The road has been long and the sacrifices have been great.
True. We have lost the lance of Lajonus.
And now unit zero.
That is sufficient reason for removing Akari.
Surely he must have understood what the release of the Utsuki meant.
We shall have to find another cat's paw to use against Akari.
And this one must know the truth.
The Roswell explicities are left with Matt and 출.
But then a junior at firstkline, we may have to be determined to have loan paid for each other.
How does the current facility mean to be made in my house?
lights, smith, dia can come in.
We did not look for it in ourhangs.
Misato, I can't cry anymore.
I feel the pain, but the tears won't come.
Why is that?
Shinji, I don't know what to do or say.
All I can do is be here for you.
Don't touch me!
Just leave me alone, Misato.
I'm sorry.
I know how lonely he must be.
Does the fact that I'm a woman frighten him?
Or is he afraid of getting close to anyone?
Pen-pen, come here.
It's true.
Anything is better than being alone.
And I'm the one who's lonely.
Hello?
Yes?
What?
Shinji!
Dr. Odani, 1st Internal Division, Dr. Odani.
Please call Conference Room 2 immediately.
Ray!
I'm so glad.
I can't believe you're alive.
Why isn't my father here?
Anyway, thank you for saving my life.
For doing what?
You saved me.
By sacrificing Unit Zero.
Oh, did I save you?
Don't you remember?
I just don't know.
I think, I think I must be the third one.
I'm seeing this for the first time, and yet, this feels like this is not the first time.
Why am I crying?
What am I crying for?
Yes, that's right.
Put a hold on Ray's, on the first child's current status.
Just keep your eyes on.
Nothing more.
The fact that Ray is even alive is likely to cause a great deal of trouble with Chairman Keele.
I've given the old men of Zele something else to look at.
There is no problem.
It is our intent to carry out this inquisition in a dignified manner.
It is not our intent to bring any shame upon you.
I don't feel any shame.
She is a strong woman.
I can see why Ikari wants to keep her next to him.
However, were you aware the one who sent you here was none other than Ikari himself?
He refused our request for the pilot of Unit Zero, and has sent you here in her stead, Dr. Akagi.
He sent me instead of her?
The way to the truth, which you wanted, was sent by 36 other methods, but they won't reach you.
The only way that is guaranteed is this capsule.
This is all I have.
Now it's completely up to you as to how to use this.
The passcode is our first memory.
Goodbye.
And take care.
The silence from you no longer hurts as much as it once did.
Not since you gave me your heart and soul.
So, has Dr. Akagi's deposition proved acceptable?
She is not like Piuski.
It is more beneficial for us to release her.
The woman has rendered remarkable service to the Eva series.
Let it continue to be of use for a while.
For the future of mankind.
As for the Evangelions themselves, there are now eight under construction.
And four that are not.
The disappearance of Tokyo 3 will prove to be a boon to the project.
We must accelerate to completion.
On that day, the promised time will be at hand.
Hello?
Listen to me carefully.
For the next few minutes, you'll be free from the secret service.
Come here now while you can.
Rizko?
Sorry, it won't work without my password.
I see.
Did Kaji arrange this?
Show them to me.
All the secrets you buried here.
All right.
But this one will see them as well.
Agreed.
This looks just like Rey's room.
That's not surprising.
This is the place where Rey was born.
She was what?
She was born here.
The visions of light and water that stream through her consciousness are merely reflections of this place.
Dr. Akagi, this isn't what I came to see.
I know that, Misato.
Is that Aunt Ava?
The first one.
A failure.
We abandoned it ten years ago.
A graveyard for Avas.
Nothing that elaborate.
Just a dumping ground.
It's also the place where your mother was taken from you.
You may not remember it, but you were watching at the very moment when your mother disappeared.
Do you remember that, Shinji?
Dr. Akagi, this is the core of a dummy plug?
This is where we produce the components.
Oh my God!
It's Rey!
They're all Rey!
You mean the dummy plugs are...
Uh-huh.
These are the cores of the dummy plugs.
They're what makes the system work.
Who are they?
These?
These are empty vessels.
Nothing but spare parts.
Spare rays.
Mankind found a God and man.
In his folly, tried to make the God his toy.
For that arrogance, mankind was punished.
That happened fifteen years ago.
And the God that man found was lost.
But man continues to attempt to resurrect the God.
And from that God, Adam, man attempted to make a man who was like a God himself.
And that was Ava.
What?
Avas are human?
Yes.
Inside the empty shell of each Ava is a human soul.
But the only vessel which can hold a soul is Rey.
These things are empty husks.
They have no souls.
No right to live.
The room of God is empty.
Stop this!
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Yes, I know.
I'm destroying them.
These aren't human.
Just things with human forms.
But even so,
I lost to these things.
To these soulless dolls.
I couldn't win.
I could have suffered any humiliation.
Endured any torture.
But he had already chosen.
God, I'm a fool.
Like mother, like daughter.
Fools to the end.
If you want to kill me, go ahead and do it.
I'd welcome death.
If that's what you want, you are a fool.
What is this curse that consumes those who come into contact with Ava?
Ava?
Fly me to the moon
And let me play
Among the stars
Let me see
Where spring is il y
On Jupiter
In other worlds
And let the words
Hold my hand
Duly kiss me
Fill my heart with song
And let me sing forever love
You are all I long for
All my words
In other words
Please be true
I love you
The city and friends that he had been protecting are gone
But now a new friend smiles upon him in the twilight
Shinji gives himself over to that smile
And it's as if all the sins that he's ever committed are gone
But fate has yet another cruel trick in store
You